Valli Sri Lalita Eranki

(949)-302-3849

https://github.com/Lalitaeranki

https://lalitaeranki.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lalitaeranki

Irvine, CA

Email:lalitaeranki@gmail.com

About Me

Data Scientist| Electrical Engineer

Former Electrical Engineer with six years teaching experience in Electrical Engineering and a passionate Data Analyst. Seeking a full time or part time position to utilize newly acquired skills in Data Analytics and abilities in an organization that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

Technical Skills

• Languages: Python, Pandas, NumPy, PyMongo, Flask, R, MATLAB, C

• Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

• Web: HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

• Visualization Tools: Matplotlib, D3.js, Plotly.js, Leaflet, Gmaps, Tableau

Simulation Tools: Simulink, PSIM Electronics Simulation Software

Web Interfaces: JSON, Beautiful Soup, APIs

• Spreadsheets: Excel, VBA, Tableau

• Others: Optimization tools, Machine Learning, GitHub, Heroku, ANN ,Hadoop,PySpark

Projects

Suicide Assessment and Analysis:

An interactive website to assess suicide risk, awareness and study the suicide rates from countries all over the world.

Skills: Pandas, Python, Flask, MongoDB, Beautiful Soup, Plotly, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Heroku.

Traffic-Violation-Analytics:

The purpose of this project was to analyses whether the traffic stops and citations by Police is biased on Gender and Race in Pandas.

Skills: Pandas, Python, Jupyter Notebook, NumPy.

Belly Button Biodiversity:

An interactive dashboard to investigate the microbes inhabiting our navels and the factors using Plotly.js. Skills: Python, Pandas, Flask, SQLAlchemy, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Heroku.

Web Scraping-Mission to Mars:

Web application that scrapes various websites for data related to Mars and displays the information in a single HTML page.

Skills :Python, Flask, Jupyter Notebook, MongoDB, PyMongo, Pandas, Splinter, Beautiful Soup, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku

Reliability evaluation of committed units in conventional and fuzzy approach:

In this project, a program in Matlab is developed for a probabilistic approach for hierarchical level-I (HL-I) reliability of unit commitment problem (UC). With the proposed methods, uncertainties embedded in generation side are taken into account and then the reliability indices such as loss-of-load-probability (LOLP) and fuzzy loss-of-load-probability (FLOLP) have been evaluated. A short-term commitment period with a 24-hour time horizon is considered.

Skills: MATLAB 6.1, Simulink.

Professional Experience

GHRCEM (Pune, India)

Aug-2010 - April 2013

- Lecturer in Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department.
- Subjects Taught: Power Electronics, Electric Drives and Control, Basic Electrical engineering.
- Taken Laboratory course in Electrical Machines Power Electronics, Electric Drives.

SNSIT (Hyderabad, India)

Aug-2009 - Feb 2010

- Lecturer in Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department.
- Subjects Taught: Electric Circuits, Power Systems Analysis, Electrical Machines, Basic Electrical engineering
- Taken Laboratory course in Electrical Machines, Electrical Circuits, Networks

ICFAITECH (Hyderabad, India)

May-2005 – August-2006

- Lecturer in Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department.
- Subjects Taught: Power Systems Analysis, Switchgear and Protection, Electrical Machines, Basic Electrical engineering
- Taken Laboratory course in Power System Analysis based on power world Simulator
- Guided students in presenting Technical Reports
- Handled Projects both short and long term in Matlab6.1.

Rungta College of Engineering. And Technology (Bhilai, India)

March-2002 - July-2002

- Lecturer in Electrical Engineering Department.
- Subjects Taught: Electrical Machines, Basic Electrical engineering, Network Synthesis
- Handled labs in Electrical Machines
- Short term projects in C.

Education

<u>UC Irvine</u> 2018-2019

Certificate, The Data Science and Visualization Boot Camp

Birla Institute of Technology MESRA, India

2002-2004

Master of Engineering in POWER SYSTEMS

B.I.T.DURG, PT.Ravishankar Shukla University,India

1997-2001

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical Engineering

Awards

Received EXCEL GOLD MEDAL from B.I.T., DURG for securing highest percentage in Electrical Engineering. Branch for session 97-2001.

Technical Paper

SOLUTION OF UNIT COMMITMENT USING MODIFIED GENETIC ALGORITHM CONSIDERING THE EFFECT OF UNIT OUTAGE UNCERTAINTY-**Journal** (203) International Journal of Power and Energy Systems - 2008.